Let's organize what happened so far.
我們粗略回顧一下前面劇情
Oh, we're not parodying anyone with our look.
我們沒有在模仿誰喔
We're not.
沒有喔
Episode One. Mom's series is canceled by Saneisha.
第一集
No sign of a love interest.
被散英社甩了
Episode Two, Mom's rejected by Doctor Wataru.
第二集，媽媽被涉師傅甩了
Episode Three, Mom is rejected by her last resort,
第三集，連媽媽最後的備胎
her childhood friend Gon-chan.
兒時玩伴阿欣也甩了她
This show shouldn't be called Date My Daughter!
這部不是講我家女兒交不到男朋友
You're the one not finding anybody.
而是你交不到男朋友的故事吧
It should be called Date Me!
應該改叫《我交不到男朋友》吧
Come on, say it.
來，你自己說一次
Date Me!
我交不到男朋友
DATE ME!
（我交不到男朋友！）
What is this horrible title?
這標題太羞辱人了吧
No one would approve of this title. Not a station, not society.
這個標題不給過
-A station? -TV station.
-台？ -電視台
Your title has lies!
標題詐騙！
That's not true! I'll find a boyfriend!
才不是！今天這集就會有了
I'll find someone! I'll get a boyfriend!
我會交到男友，一定可以！
You hear that, folks?
這是她說的
You're the one without a boyfriend.
交不到男友的人是你
What?
什麼？
Date my daughter!
《我家女兒交不到男朋友！》
Thank you for coming today.
恭候多時了
Room 808, right?
在808，對吧？
How did you know?
您怎麼知道？
It's Saneisha's fanciest meeting room.
因為那是散英社最豪華的接待室
DON'T FORGET ME
（《勿忘我》）
We're so sorry!
對不起
What's going on? You told them the time, right?
怎麼回事？
-Sorry about this. -It's fine. Is it the show, Glaring Sun?
真抱歉
No, that already ended. Now, it's Friendly Family.
那是前一部
Keep it quiet.
消息還沒正式公布
They're saving him until Part Two.
好像是後半部的隱藏王牌
He's here.
他抵達了
Sorry for the wait.
抱歉，讓大家久等了
Ms. Minase, right?
你就是水無瀨老師吧？
You're more beautiful and youthful than in the photos.
你比照片上看起來更年輕貌美
I'm Yuto.
我是悠人
You really are beautiful.
你真的好美
Well…
哪有…
So,
那麼
I wanted to ask you something today.
今天我想拜託老師一件事
What?
什麼？
Don't Forget Me will be turned into a movie?
《勿忘我》要拍成電影啊
And with Silent Knife? Cool!
能邀請到Silent Knife 真是太厲害了
Yes. Mom's at the meeting with him right now.
嗯，我媽今天去跟他開會
She got all dolled up.
全身穿得超華麗時髦
Silent Night? What the heck is that?
什麼是Silent Night？
Silent Knife.
Silent Knife啦
-Yuto, don't you know? He's super popular. -Oh.
-就是悠人啊，現在正火紅的悠人 -是喔
Mom is a big fan! She was all pumped up this morning
我媽是他的超級粉絲，特地盛裝打扮
and she got all dressed up.
還戴這樣的帽子
-Her hat is this big! Like this… -Um… Hello.
-這樣… -打擾了
Welcome!
歡迎光臨
Found you.
找到你了
I wanted to explain myself.
我覺得自己應該好好向你解釋
Why…
為什麼…
Why?
為什麼你要在約會時故意裝假鼻毛？
I wore this
這就是我用的假鼻毛
This is new. I haven't used it yet, so it's clean.
這是新的
It's a two in one set.
一組有兩個
This is the nose hair extension?
這就是假鼻毛嗎？
-Can I try it on? -What?
-我可以戴看看嗎？ -什麼？
Oh, sure, but…
是可以啦
How is it?
怎麼樣？
It's kind of cute.
有點可愛
It's not cute, but…
這不是可愛吧…
It's realistic.
好真實
I'm sorry! It was so rude of me!
我對你做了很過分的事，對不起
I was
我是故意想惹你討厭
Why?
為什麼？
There's someone I can't forget.
我有個無法忘懷的人
I can't forget this person.
我不能忘了她
So I wanted to avoid
所以萬一
the really improbable case
萬一你真的喜歡上我的話
I wanted to make sure that this date didn't go well.
因此我一定要讓那次約會失敗
Then why did you ask me to go see the otters?
那你為什麼要邀我去看小爪水獺？
Because I wanted to see the otters.
我想看小爪水獺
With you.
想跟你一起去
But you have someone you can't forget, right?
但你有不能忘記的人吧？
Then, I wish you would've told me.
那你一開始就應該跟我說清楚
It's so sneaky to try to be hated
故意露出鼻毛讓我生厭什麼的
by showing your nose hair.
太被動了
It's so patronizing.
感覺很瞧不起人
That's not what I…
-我沒那個意思 -感覺…
I was treated as a child.
好像被當成小孩子
I feel like I was belittled.
彷彿自己受到輕視
I…
我…
Goodbye.
再見
For the first time in my life,
我有生以來第一次 對男人說再見並轉身離開
It felt a little like I was the heroine of a story.
感覺好像成了什麼女主角
It felt good.
心情滿痛快的
Nine parts sad, one part good.
九成的哀傷，一成的痛快
The ratio of my heart.
就是我內心的比例
I don't think I'm saying anything difficult.
我的話應該不難理解吧
The girlfriend dies at the end of Don't Forget Me, right?
女主角在《勿忘我》的最後 不是死了嗎？
I wanted it to be that only I die.
我只是想改成我死而已
Then what about the title?
那標題怎麼辦？
The "me" would be me.
勿忘“俺”？
I think that's a great idea.
好像很不錯呢
-I think it's good. -What?
-我覺得這標題很好喔 -啊？
The movie production company
電影公司的高層
and the producer and the screenwriter,
製作人跟編劇
they all agree, right?
大家都能接受吧？
Yes.
當然
The company agrees with this plot change.
公司那邊也能接受
It's better if I'm the one to die.
因為死掉的人最吃香啊
Then the girls would go, "Oh no! Yuto's dying!"
女生就會哭著說：“悠人要死掉了”
It's not Yuto. It's Shuji.
不是悠人，是修二
Oh, the name?
名字啊
The name doesn't matter.
名字無所謂吧
Yes, sir. The script is already written with this plot change.
是啊
What?
什麼？
Without my consent?
未經我這位原作者許可就寫了嗎？
Oh? Did I not mention it to you?
咦？我沒說嗎？
I don't like
別這麼嚴肅說什麼許可的啦
I don't want to use words like that between us.
我們之間就別這麼說了吧
Maybe you don't need my original text then.
就算不用我的書也沒關係吧
It's a different story, after all.
因為這根本是不同的劇情了
No, no.
那怎麼行？
It has to be your work.
一定得用老師的作品才行
The lines you write are awesome. Right?
畢竟裡面的台詞真的很棒啊，對吧？
Yes, I wrote them down.
是啊…很多名言佳句喔
I picked out all the best parts, Ms. Minase.
我們都有放進去喔，水無瀨老師
"You only meet someone once. Once you meet them, you can't meet them"
“相遇的機會只有一次”
-"for the first time ever again." -I want to say lines like that.
-“一旦遇上了就無法再重來” -我想說這一句
That's Naoko's line.
那是奈緒子的台詞
Hey, listen…
-所以我說… -時間差不多了
So let's just swap the male and female characters.
我要對調男女主角的戲份
I'll be the one to die.
最後死的是我
Sorry, Ms. Minase.
老師，抱歉
I have a recording session now.
我接下來還要去錄音
I'm so busy. I hate it!
忙死了，真討厭
I'm excited to stand next to you when this film is done, Ms. Minase.
殺青記者會
See ya.
改天見
So, Ms. Aoi. You know how it is.
小碧老師，事情就這樣說定了
This movie is a big opportunity for you, too.
這部電影對您而言也是大好機會
The world will know about Aoi Minase once again.
能讓世人再次認識水無瀨碧這個名字
We'll push our marketing, too.
宣傳時也會大力推水無瀨碧喔
You know, Ms. Aoi.
另外，小碧老師
We're still waiting on your proposal for your new book.
您遲遲還沒提出下一本書的企劃啊
We have a limit to
我們每年的新書數都是固定的
We have a lot of writers who want to publish through us.
有很多作家都想在我們出版社出書
You know what I'm saying. We're all adults here.
您明白吧？這是大人的規矩啊
Thank you for helping us make this movie.
請您務必答應電影化
Manga, the internet, games…
漫畫、網路、遊戲
Literary Department's being
浪潮一波接一波
pushed out everywhere.
文藝也不好混啊
Hey, you.
喂
Did you know about this?
你早就知道了嗎？
No. But I thought it was weird that we'd meet Yuto so soon.
我不知道
I came here to get this autographed.
我還帶這個來想給他簽名
I'm so stupid!
我好像笨蛋！
Let's speak out against this. And stop this film.
我們提出抗議吧
You didn't hear what Konishi said?
你有聽到剛才小西說什麼嗎？
It's an agreement!
這是條件交換
I have to give over my rights.
如果我不交出這本書
Otherwise, they won't publish my new book. That's what he said.
出版社就不給我機會刊登下一篇文章
That's not right.
這樣也說不過去啊
Ms. Aoi, we have to strategize.
小碧老師，我們來擬定戰略吧
I've hit my peak already. No one cares about my stuff!
我已經過氣了
We have to accept this movie with these wild conditions.
若不接受這種胡鬧的電影企劃
Otherwise, I can't keep on writing!
我就會失去下一個舞台
Excuse me, Ms. Aoi,
小碧老師，請恕我直言
but the publishing industry is suffering everywhere.
全球出版業都很辛苦
Reality is even worse.
現實生活更是殘酷
A lot of writers get part-time jobs, because they can't get work…
有些作家沒工作
Who do you think I am?
你當我是誰啊？
I'm Aoi Minase.
我可是水無瀨碧
Will you leave me alone for a bit?
請你讓我獨處一下
Leave me alone for a bit!
請你讓我獨處一下！
I understand.
我知道了
DON'T FORGET ME
（《勿忘我》）
I wanted to clean up inside.
我要進去整理茶杯
It's still in use.
接待室還在用
HAPPY KANAKO'S KILLER LIFE
（《加奈子的幸福殺手生活》）
There's someone I can't forget.
我有個無法忘懷的人
What's wrong with me?
我是怎麼了？
I can't laugh at my favorite lines.
這裡我通常都會大笑的
I'm home!
我回來了
Welcome home.
歡迎回家
We're so sorry!
非常抱歉！
-What? -We thought we could finally
-什麼？ -還以為終於能讓天國的菜子安心了
We're so sorry!
-真是對不起 -怎麼現在才這麼說？
I already bought a white tuxedo at Marunouchi for the wedding!
我已經去丸之內大樓買燕尾服了
What's going on here?
請問事情怎麼會變成這樣？
Well, Miss Aoba was very pretty, right?
這個嘛，青葉小姐是個大美女吧？
Yes. Very much so.
這倒是真的
In Roppongi, in the residence area where people live,
六本木區，有人住的住宅區那邊
she attended a party with rich people that live in that area.
很多有錢人會在那裡開派對
A CEO of an IT company fell smitten with her.
-結果有位IT公司社長看上她 -她跟我兒子…
after meeting with my son?
跟小犬相親後還去參加那種派對嗎？
Apparently it's common.
這種事好像很正常喔
A professional girlfriend, do they call it? They search
那是叫職業女友嗎？
I thought she struck for Gon!
她不是對阿欣出手了嗎？
She did, but she found an even better one after that!
是啊…只是後來又遇到更好的
Maybe she clapped twice, like clap clap!
所以是出兩次手
It seems like
她說她在這裡看到阿欣
and visiting the shop to see you.
對你一見鍾情也是謊話
Looks like she was
她只是看上這裡的資產價值
How much this place is worth when you sell it.
就是在盤算賣掉這裡能拿到多少錢啦
Hey, Mrs. Toyoda. You're the one spilling all the tea!
豐田，你真是大嘴巴耶
Land prices are going up. You know, with Takanawa Gateball?
這附近的地價正在上漲
The new Yamanote Line station they're making!
就是那個山手線準備新蓋的車站
It's Takanawa Gateway!
是高輪Gateway啦
Can't play gateball at a station!
在車站玩什麼槌球啦！
So in other words, our home is worth a lot of money.
總之就是我們若賣掉這裡 會拿到很多錢嗎？
She was after your money!
她看上的是錢啦
I'm glad it didn't work out! She's like a sly fox!
真是萬幸啊
She was way too young and pretty for you, you know?
她對阿欣來說也太年輕貌美了啦
-Right? -Yes!
-對吧？ -對啊
You two just say what you wan't, don't you?
你們真是口無遮攔啊
60 orders of taiyaki!
六十份鯛魚燒！
To apologize, Mrs.Toyoda and Mrs. Kanbayashi
豐田阿姨跟神林阿姨為了賠罪
placed a big order for taiyaki and went home.
買了一大堆鯛魚燒回家
-What should I do with this? -I'll wear it.
-那這該怎麼辦啊？ -我來穿吧
Dad, you're getting married?
咦？你要結婚嗎？
I'm just saying, you don't know what'll happen in life.
人生就是無法預測 未來會發生什麼事啊
You scared me.
嚇我一跳
You look relieved.
你也鬆了一口氣吧
Why would I be relieved?
我幹嘛鬆一口氣？
Because you were trying to get married for Nako.
因為你是為了菜子才決定結婚
Not for yourself.
並不是為了自己
"This place,
“這裡
this spot next to me including Odaya,
包含小田屋在內，你的身邊
I want to reserve that spot for Aoi."
其實是想留給小碧的”
What are you saying? Have you gone senile?
亂說什麼啊？
When you say mean things like that,
你每次講話變惡毒時
it means I'm right.
就是被人說中了
Don't say dumb things. Why would I be with that tomboy?
你別亂說啦 我怎麼可能喜歡那種粗魯的女孩？
She's been too old to be called a tomboy. And she gained weight…
她早就不是女孩了
I knew all along.
我看得出來喔
When you came back from France,
你為什麼會從法國回到日本
when you left Étoile and came home…
為什麼會從埃蒂華身邊回來這裡
Gon-chan used to be married to a Parisienne named Étoile
阿欣以前
He fell in love
他去環遊世界時墜入愛河了
That happened because Étoile got with
我都說了
And in front of Notre Dame, no less!
就在聖母院前面
On the surface, that's what happened.
表面上也許是這樣
But you came back for Aoi.
但是你又回到小碧身邊了
It was all decided
這是上天的安排啊
I can't keep up with your romantic nonsense! I'm going to go take a bath.
真欽佩你有這種浪漫的想法
SUZURAN HOT SPRINGS
（鈴蘭溫泉）
Gon-chan!
阿欣，你可以不要嫁別人嗎？
Ah, god!
真是的！
On the surface, it's a good bet.
我覺得附加的效果並不差
-A bet? -The big production movie.
-附加效果？ -將會是部大片
It'll be distributed by Kamisaka.
是由業界最大的上坂公司發行
The theme song will of course be by the extremely popular Silent Knife.
主題曲當然也是由氣勢如虹的 Silent Knife來唱
The director is Shinji Iwata. He's done many popular films.
導演更是連續拍出 許多賣座電影的岩田真二
This could make a billion yen, at least.
十億應該跑不掉
Considering Yuto's popularity,
再加上悠人現在的人氣
some say we could even aim for ten billion.
相關人士甚至預測可能會到百億
Anyone can speculate, right?
光說大話誰不會啊？
And we got Lili Mashiba to play Naoko.
好像也請到真柴莉莉來飾演奈緒子了
Wow! She's really popular.
好厲害，她不是當紅女星嗎？
Yes, so it's a good bet.
是的，所以說附加效果很不錯
But they're switching the male and female characters, right?
可是男女主角要對調吧？
Shuji dies and Naoko lives.
修二會死，奈緒子會活著
Yes. That's the absolute requirement set by Yuto.
是的
Don't Forget Me, with the two characters reversed.
關於男女主角戲份對調的 《勿忘我》劇情
This is the storyline.
我想好故事大綱了
What?
什麼？
I tested the script
我檢查過了
to see if the story would work with the roles reversed.
男女主角對調後是否符合邏輯
I understand that this was rude,
我知道這樣做很冒犯
but I changed some parts.
但我有修改了幾個橋段
How long did this take you?
你花了幾天寫這個啊？
Three days.
三天
You haven't slept, have you?
都沒睡吧？
I'm fine.
我還撐得住
But, I'm sorry.
對不起
In my "Don't Forget Me,"
我所寫的《勿忘我》
Naoko has to die. That's the story.
講的是奈緒子最後死亡的故事
And Shuji has to live.
也是修二繼續活著的故事
Let's say no, then.
不然別拍電影了
I want money, and I want a place to publish my next book.
我想要錢
I want to publish my next book!
我想要下一個舞台
Listen.
我跟你說
My best work is always my next work.
我的代表作是下一本作品
My next work always has to be the greatest work.
我的下一本作品 應該永遠都要是最棒的傑作
I heard rumors.
我耳聞了一些消息
Is it true you plagiarized?
你真的有抄襲過嗎？
You worked in manga, right? Shonen Up of Saneisha.
你之前是隸屬散英社的 《少年UP》漫畫部吧
You turned Zephyr and Shinogi into big hits, right?
還幫《Zephyr》 跟《江湖生活》闖出名號
Yes.
是的
Then, you ran out of ideas for Young Monster
後來因為《少年怪獸》的 劇情發展沒有靈感
and plagiarized plot points from a book published abroad.
你就直接抄襲國外的小說
You made the manga artist write it as if it were your own ideas.
騙漫畫家說那是你的點子 讓他用在漫畫裡
Yuzuru Yube. He's very famous.
由邊讓老師是很有名的漫畫家呢
This was big news back in the day.
當時風波鬧得很大
Everyone's forgotten, but I read about it in Bunshun.
大眾可能不記得了
I didn't know that was you.
沒想到那個人就是你
That's why you got transferred from manga to literary.
你因為這樣從漫畫部轉到文藝部
And now, you're my editor.
接著成為我的責編
We're both failures, aren't we?
我們是失敗者雙人組呢
I've never plagiarized, though.
雖然我是沒抄襲過別人的作品啦
You're not a failure, Ms. Aoi. You're a Tiffany.
老師不是失敗者 您是Tiffany
What?
什麼？
You're the real thing, who doesn't lose against the times
您是不會輸給歲月浪潮 與世間紛擾的真材實料
You write novels that are loved
您能寫出跨越世代 受到大家喜愛的小說
Excuse me.
我先告辭了
Wait a minute! Oh! Not there!
等一下，和生，不可以
You can't go there!
別去那邊，不行
Sorry, you're busy. I'll call you back.
抱歉，你在忙嗎？我等一下再打
It's fine. My daughter will be back soon.
沒關係，我女兒去剪頭髮 就快回來了
No, you've got it wrong!
事情不是那樣子
What? I'm wrong?
咦？不是嗎？
You are! This is about Young Monster, right?
完全不是
It was Yuzuru Yube who plagiarized.
那是由邊讓老師自己抄襲的
But Shonen Up publishes abroad, too.
因為《少年UP》有在海外販售
The writer themselves found it, and sued.
原作者發現之後向他提告
Soseki took the blame,
後來是漱石說
so that Yuzuru Yube's name
不能因此傷到由邊讓老師的聲譽
won't be tainted.
才替他頂罪的
Seriously?
真假？
But that's unfair for the company to transfer Soseki!
那公司還罰他調職也太過分了
Ms. Aoi, that's what working at a company is like.
小碧老師，所謂的大公司
It's full of unfairness and injustices.
就是不公不義的暴風雨啊
Well,
這倒是…
I did think that when you volunteered
我聽到像你這麼優秀的人 居然決定提早退休
So Soseki's innocent.
所以漱石是清白的
Oh no! What should I do?
怎麼辦？
I really cornered him!
我對他說了超重的話
Like I was placing stones
彷彿是放了一顆重石
on the lap of a violent criminal!
在罪不可赦的罪犯腿上
I don't know what that means, but Soseki's innocent.
我聽不懂你在說什麼 總之漱石是清白的
But you know, you know?
因為我…
Listen to me, Matsuyama.
因為我…松山，你聽我說
When I'm with him, I end up saying everything that's on my mind!
我老是會忍不住對他說出真心話
Even things I don't need to say out loud!
連沒有必要說的話 也都會忍不住說出口
"I want money, I want a place to publish, my greatest work is my next work…"
像是我想要錢，想要下一個舞台
So embarrassing! Totally embarrassing!
丟臉，我太丟臉了
I blabbed on about embarrassing things,
我說了很多不爭氣的話
which made me hate him, which made me aggressive.
所以擅自覺得他很討厭 很想講話攻擊他
I wanted to corner him.
很想爭贏他
Ms. Aoi, are you doing it again?
小碧老師 您的老毛病是不是又犯了？
What?
什麼？
You aren't falling for him, are you?
您不會是喜歡上他了吧？
No, I don't think so.
這不可能
No way, no way, Nile crocodile?
不可能…
NILE CROCODILE
（尼羅鱷）
Yup.
嗯
Let's get Korean cheese hot dogs!
去吃起司熱狗吧
Good idea! The one that stretches, right?
好主意，起司能拉超長的那種吧？
-Good idea, dawg! -Irino!
-熱狗 -入野
Hey.
同學
Can we talk?
打擾一下
Come in, come in.
請進吧
You just work here part-time, right?
你只是打工的吧？
-You act like it's your own house. Ouch! -Welcome!
說得好像自己家…好痛
SANMAYAKI, 180 YEN
（秋刀魚燒 180日圓）
Should I get taiyaki or sanmayaki?
鯛魚燒跟秋刀魚燒
Why are you staring at the menu like that?
不用這麼認真研究菜單吧？
You work here. You have it memorized.
你在這打工，應該早就倒背如流了吧
Huh?
什麼？
Looking at it and thinking hard about what to get is the fun part.
就是要努力思考 “我要選哪一個呢？”
-Hey. -Ken, water, please!
-那個… -阿健，幫我上水
Coming right up!
好
-Here's water. -Two taiyaki, please.
-水來了 -兩份鯛魚燒
I haven't had lunch. I want yakisoba.
我還沒吃飯呢
If so, pay for yourself. I'm broke.
炒麵你自己付錢，我缺錢
You brought me all the way here!
咦？明明是你拖我來的
But it's okay because the food's good here.
算了，反正這裡很好吃
One yakisoba, please.
-我自己買一份炒麵 -謝謝惠顧
Don't you get sick of working with this?
跟這種人共事是不是很煩？
Ouch!
好痛！
Ow…
痛死了
So, what is it?
幹嘛啦？
There's a reason I brought you here.
我找你來是有原因的
I didn't want to show you this near the school.
我不好意思在學校附近拿給你看
They'd figure out you're an otaku.
而且大家還會發現你是宅男
I did some sketches.
我試著畫了
What?
什麼？
I drew some sketches.
我試著畫出來了
A country, not here, not in the present.
非此時此地的某個國家
A country where stories are forbidden.
受故事禁令束縛的某個國家
So cool!
太厲害了！
-Really? -The concept sketches! This is it!
-真的嗎？ -對啊，概念草圖都完成了
Is this right?
怎麼樣？有符合嗎？
Yes, totally.
符合，很符合
I can't think up of things like this myself.
換作是我完全想不到這些畫面
It was this blurry image in my head.
要怎麼形容？
But now it's here, in front of me!
化成了具體的型態
You're amazing, you!
你這傢伙太強了
My name's not "you."
別叫我“這傢伙”
Miss Minase? Her Majesty?
水無瀨同學？大大？
Oh, Her Highness?
水無瀨氏…
Just Minase's fine.
入野氏，叫我水無瀨就好啦
Irino's fine for me, too.
你也叫我入野就好
This solidifies my image so much!
腦中開始浮現具體的畫面了
I can think of so many stories now!
湧出好多故事的靈感
I'll go home and edit.
我回去再重新想想
Wait, you…
咦？
You'll draw with me? I thought you were busy with your date.
你要跟我一起創作嗎？
Oh, right. The nose hair ended it.
因為鼻毛告吹了吧
It was nose hair extensions.
那是假鼻毛
Nose hair extensions?
假鼻毛？
He wanted to be hated by me because
因為他有無法忘懷的人
he has someone he can't forget.
所以故意要讓我討厭他
What the hell?
什麼？
The day I heard that,
我聽完他的解釋之後
my insides were spinning.
整個人頭暈腦脹的
Around here. It kept on spinning around.
這裡
"That pisses me off!" "It feels like I'm spinning!"
我覺得很生氣
I wanted to forget about all that.
我想要趕快忘掉這種糾結的感覺
So I drew what I could think of
所以就試著將你說的概念
for your concept art.
照我腦中的想法畫出來了
He wanted to be hated, because there's someone he can't forget?
因為有無法忘懷的人
Yes.
對
Why doesn't he call her "the person he likes," or his girlfriend?
為什麼他不說是喜歡的人呢？
Which means, it's not like he likes anyone,
既不是說有喜歡的人
and it's not like he has a girlfriend.
也不是說女友
You're observant, and smart.
你好敏銳，一針見血
You're right.
的確
Maybe it's an ex that he can't forget.
還是無法忘懷的前女友呢？
In that case,
若是那樣
why can't he forget them?
為什麼不能忘記呢？
You can forget ex-girlfriends.
忘了以前的女友也沒關係吧
Are you a pro at romance?
你是戀愛專家嗎？
I've only experienced
我只懂一些膚淺的戀愛啦
Surface-level romance?
膚淺的戀愛？
Romance that was dishonest.
例如壞壞的戀愛？
What's dishonest love?
什麼是壞壞的戀愛？
How do I say it?
該怎麼說呢？
Love that happened thoughtlessly.
像是一口氣進展那樣 對，就是一口氣進展型
You mean, it started with sex?
從肉體關係開始的那種嗎？
Don't say that with such twinkling eyes.
別兩眼發光地說出來啦
I'm encountering the Unknown.
發現未知生物
Here you are!
久等了
I'll be heading home now. Thank you.
那我差不多該走了，感謝招待
You ate a lot again,
小碧，你今天胃口也很好啊
I'm stress eating.
-我用吃洩憤啦 -別一直鑽牛角尖喔
-You're right. -Yeah.
-也是啊 -嗯
Because you're getting married to Aoba.
你不是要跟青葉小姐結婚了嗎？
About that, Aoi. A lot happened, and…
小碧，後來發生了一些事…
Just enjoy the moment! Keep my smile in your memories.
好好享受當下吧
What are you saying?
聽不懂你在說什麼
-I'll be back! -Don't come back!
-我改天再來 -別再來了
-Be nice to your dad! -Oh.
你居然這樣對老爸
Sora, you're here?
小空，你也來啦
Mom, your inner monologue is coming out. Turn it off.
媽媽，你講出你的心聲了
You're Aoi Minase, right?
您是水無瀨碧本人吧？
I'm such a big fan! My mom was a big fan of yours originally.
哇，我是您的書迷
I've read your books!
我…我都有看您的作品
Oh my!
真不好意思
Sorry about that. I'm Hikaru Irino.
失禮了
-I'm so moved! -Excuse me.
-哇，我太感動了 -不好意思
Are you still doing lunch?
還能點午餐嗎？
Yes, come in.
沒問題，請坐
Doctor Wataru!
喔，涉師傅
What is this? A comedy sketch?
這發展也太像松竹新喜劇了吧？
I don't even watch comedy.
雖然我沒看過
The nose hair extensions you told me about,
上次你告訴我的那個鼻毛
they're so funny! It was a big hit.
實在太好玩了，看過的人都笑到不行
-This is the nose hair guy? -Nose hair guy?
-鼻毛就是他嗎？ -鼻毛？
Why is everyone calling me nose hair guy?
怎麼大家都對著我說鼻毛鼻毛的？
Come in, please sit! We only have yakisoba.
快請坐吧，不過炒麵剛賣完
Thank you.
不好意思
No nose hair today?
你今天沒有裝假鼻毛嗎？
-Well… -Who's this person you can't forget?
-沒有 -請問你無法忘懷的人是誰？
-Your ex-girlfriend? -What?
-前女友嗎？ -你幹嘛啦？
She took it hard. She was spinning.
因為這個人心裡糾結成一團 心情很鬱悶喔
-Yeah, you were sad! -Don't intervene, Mom!
-對啊，她很消沉 -媽媽不要插嘴！
I'm not a kid anymore.
我已經不是小孩了
Oh, I'm sorry.
對不起
What's going on? I'm lost.
怎麼了？我怎麼都聽不懂？
What? What happened?
什麼？發生什麼事？
It's not a girlfriend, or someone I like.
對方不是我女友，也不是我喜歡的人
But…
可是…
It's someone you can't forget.
是無法忘懷的人吧
It's more like, someone I shouldn't forget.
應該說是不能忘記的人
I know! Maybe she's dead!
我知道了
Is your girlfriend dead?
你的戀人死掉了嗎？
Or a dead fiancé, maybe?
還是未婚妻死了？
Hey, shut up! It's not a joke! It's real life!
笨蛋，這不是在猜謎，是真實的事啦
What if you were right? So insensitive!
萬一說中了怎麼辦？你太白目了
No, it's fine. She's not dead.
不是的，她沒有死
She's alive. Somewhere…
她還在世上某處活著
Somewhere?
世上某處？
We made a promise in front of the bunny cage.
我們在兔兔小屋前約好了
-Bunny cage? -Yes.
-兔兔小屋？ -是的
We were in charge of the bunnies.
我們都是負責照顧兔子的人
We were feeding Miu together.
總是一起去餵小咪
Miu?
小咪？
The name of the bunny.
兔子的名字啦
Doctor Wataru, how old were you?
涉師傅
I was in the third grade. I was nine.
小學三年級，九歲
Everyone went home when Miu was dying,
小咪快要死掉的那天，大家都回家了
but we stayed behind to be by her side.
只有我們兩個人留下來 一起陪著小咪
And in her final moments, Miu did a little hop.
小咪在最後跳了一下
Hey!
喂
I just imagined it in my head.
不小心想像了一下
I thought that was her way of saying thank you.
我覺得那可能是牠要表達感謝
That's not funny!
現在不是笑的時候
But she moved away.
但她後來轉學了
We promised to get married.
我們當時約好要結婚
What?
什麼？
I wanted a family.
我很想要家人
I'm not explaining correctly.
我說明得不夠清楚
I lost both my parents when I was young
其實我很小的時候
in a car accident.
父母就意外身亡了
My uncle took me in.
後來是我叔叔收養我
I'm very thankful to my uncle.
我非常感謝他
But it was different from having a real family.
只是
So I just imagined in my head
只有一起照顧兔子的女同學跟小咪
that the bunny cage girl and Miu
才是我的家人
were my real family.
是我擅自在幻想啦
A place where I can feel calm.
因為那裡是我能夠放鬆的地方
And have you met that girl?
後來那個同學呢？
No. I don't even know where she lives.
我們沒再見過面
You've loved her this whole time?
你一直掛念著她嗎？
Well, you know, I'm an adult so…
也不是，也曾年少輕狂
if someone approaches me "just to have fun," then I…
總是有人說玩玩也沒關係，所以就…
I don't need those details!
沒人問得這麼詳細啦
You wanted to keep the promise at nine years old all this time.
所以你想要一直遵守 九歲的那個約定嗎？
I felt like I had to.
我覺得自己應該遵守約定
We held hands in front of the bunny cage. It was my first time
我們還在兔兔小屋前牽手
holding hands with a girl
之前只有在跳奧克拉荷馬混合舞時 跟女孩子牽過手
I can't forget the
我無法忘記
feeling of her small hands in mine from that time.
當時她那小小手心的觸感
-Here's your yakisoba. -But…
你點的炒麵
Well, you know,
不會啦
But, Sora.
不過小空
I'm glad you have such a wonderful boyfriend.
太好了，你已經有這麼棒的男友了
That's much better than getting involved with me.
比跟我扯上關係好太多了
Sorry for intruding on your date.
我打擾你們約會了吧
I'll go to McDonald's for lunch. I'll be back.
我今天午餐改吃麥當勞
How impressive, to keep loving the same girl since third grade.
真佩服他能一直想著 國小三年級的同學
I'm sorry! Pay with this.
對不起，我用這個付
What? Wait.
等…等等
ODAYA TAIYAKI
（小田屋鯛魚燒）
Doctor Wataru!
涉師傅！
Sora.
小空
I… Um…
我…
What is it?
怎麼了？
Well…
那個
I know that I won't be enough.
我不能取代她嗎？
I completely understand that, but…
雖然我自己也很清楚
Just like how you can't
但我對涉師傅
When you fixed my glasses,
我也是
with that Soy-ppucino…
你替我修好眼鏡的時候
I can't forget it too!
我一直都忘不了當時的情景
You know, it's probably nothing compared to
雖然這完全比不上
I don't think it's a competition.
這沒有所謂的輸贏
So, in that case,
那麼，既然這樣
will you go
那你願不願意
on a date with me one more time?
再跟我約會一次呢？
Without your nose hair!
不可以裝假鼻毛
Not a fake date.
不是假約會
A real date.
而是真正的約會
You challenged a nine-year-old girl!
你向九歲小女生下戰帖了
And a girl of his past!
而且還是回憶中的女生
She's romanticized to the max! She's a strong enemy!
簡直是有極端美化牌的強敵啊
Stop it! Stop it, please!
別說了，不要再說了！
I'll only lose!
完全沒有勝算
Fight hard, Sora.
小空，加油
You're choking me! Stop!
好痛苦，不要壓我！
I was worried about how shy you were, Sora.
媽媽一直很擔心你內向的個性
Even in class, you never raised your hand to solve problems you could solve!
教學觀摩時 就算你知道答案也不敢舉手
You always dressed like you were going on stage on Parents' Day!
那是因為每次教學觀摩 你都穿得好像要上台致詞一樣
It was so embarrassing!
我覺得好丟臉
I was so moved that you ran
沒想到你今天竟然主動追出去 我太感動了
I haven't been dumped yet!
不要這麼快就判我出局啦！
Anyways, Mom was so proud you took the next step….
總之媽媽很高興你願意踏出一步…
I said, you're choking me!
都說了我無法呼吸啦！
Ouch…
痛…
Hey, Mom?
媽媽？
Oops.
不會吧？你還好嗎？
Are you crying?
你在哭嗎？
Why, all of a sudden? What should I do?
好突然，好莫名喔
I don't want the movie! I really don't!
我不想要拍成電影
I want to back out!
好想拒絕
My fans would cry!
我的書迷會哭的
I'd cry, too!
我也會哭
In the box we've had since I was born,
從我出生時就有的那些箱子裡
from all of Mom's fans.
眾多書迷寄給她的粉絲信
Mom's novels are loved
媽媽的小說
by so many people
受到許多我跟媽媽都不認識的人喜愛
Why are you calling me?
為什麼？
I'm just letting you know that
我真的準備要跟他結婚了
I'm getting married for real.
想說通知你一下
Would you come to my wedding, Hikaru?
我若邀請你，你會來參加婚禮嗎？
That would be weird.
這樣太怪了吧
Really? I think it would be funny.
會嗎？
I don't want to play around with people's emotions
我已經不想再做那種 測試別人跟自己的心意
I want to quit that.
像是在玩弄感情的事了
-Oh? -I want to be more simple.
-喔？ -我想要直接
More easy.
簡單的戀愛
Will you go on another date with me?
你願不願意再跟我約會一次呢？
What changed?
你為什麼會有這種想法？
Oh, do you have a new crush?
該不會是喜歡上哪個女孩了吧？
What?
什麼？
The edamame thrower.
丟你毛豆的那位嗎？
Did I mention that?
我有說過這件事嗎？
You did.
有啊
Because it was the first time you talked about a girl.
因為那是你第一次提起女生的事
I remembered.
所以我記得
You remember weird things.
怎麼會記得這種奇怪的事？
Okay.
好吧
I shouldn't get in the way of innocent love.
我可不能阻礙可愛年輕人的未來
I won't call.
我不會再打給你了
Yeah.
喔
I'll delete your number.
我會刪掉你的電話
Yeah. Got it.
收到
Be happy, okay?
祝你幸福
I mean it.
真的
What is it?
怎麼了？
This is unacceptable.
這太過分了吧
Oh, that?
那個啊
It makes no sense!
未免也改得太誇張了
We knew that they'd swap the guy and the girl.
的確有說要對調男女主角戲份
But why does Shuji come back to life?
但修二為什麼會死後復活？
He gets frozen, comes back to life after 30 years,
變成冷凍人後，過了30年又活過來
and gets together with Naoko's daughter? What is this?
最後跟奈緒子的女兒結婚 這是什麼劇情？
Apparently, that's Yuto's idea.
好像是悠人的點子
They say sad endings don't sell.
說是壞結局不會有票房
The film company also said that large-scale stories like that sell better.
電影公司也說 現在故事格局大一點比較受歡迎
And this scenario's full of holes!
這種劇本太多破綻了
It's full of plot contradictions.
完全不合邏輯
We got the okay from the film company
別在意啦 電影公司跟製作組都說可以了
We just have to push through!
只等著開拍了，直接開拍
We can't send this to Ms. Minase no matter what.
這麼誇張的劇本 我實在不敢拿給老師看
Huh?
什麼？
-I already did. -What?
-我已經寄給她了 -什麼？
DON'T FORGET ME
（《勿忘我》）
What is this?
這是什麼東西？
-Thank you! -Come again!
-謝謝光臨 -下次再來喔
What are you doing, Dad?
你在幹嘛？
Is someone here?
有人來了嗎？
No, no one's here.
沒有，沒人在
It's just, you know…
沒什麼啦
Oh, right!
我想起來了
I was called by Manabe from the district board.
今天商店街的真鍋理事長叫我過去
I'm going to go see him!
我出去一趟
Maybe I'll wear my Gucci coat!
要不要穿Gucci的大衣去呢？
-Oh, hello? -It's me.
-喂？ -是我，電影劇本…
Ms. Aoi, I'll call you back.
小碧老師，我待會兒回電給您
Mr. Kakei!
筧先生
Who are you?
-你是誰？ -我是散英社的橘
I'm Aoi Minase's editor.
水無瀨老師的責編
You waited outside for me? Dang.
在堵我啊？真傷腦筋
Hiro, I'm here!
阿浩，我來接你了
You're as beautiful as always!
你今天也好美
About the script…
我想請教劇本的事
What?
什麼？
Could we fix it up a little more?
可不可以請您再修改一下？
This doesn't work for us.
這樣實在不太好
Don't add post-its to someone's masterpiece!
你憑什麼在我的稿子上貼標籤？
I'm sorry about that, but…
請恕我失禮
I wanted to fill in the plot holes.
我也準備了讓故事符合邏輯的方案
What is this about?
這是哪一部？
Don't Forget Me? Oh, that?
《勿忘我》？是這部啊
I'm writing a lot of scripts.
我手上有好幾個案子
Who's in charge of this?
下井，這是誰寫的？
I think Ono and Saka were messing around with that.
好像是小野跟阿坂亂寫一通的吧
Oh, right.
知道了
You don't write them yourself?
這不是您寫的嗎？
That's not your business.
跟你沒關係吧
Okay, okay, okay…
我看看…
This is an idol movie.
就是那個偶像電影吧
This is one of those movies
這種作品
that delinquent high school kids watch
不過是鄉下的混混高中生 在等打保齡球的空檔時
in their local department store while waiting for their bowling slot.
順便去AEON百貨看的電影啦
Then, they can make fun of it.
拿來閒聊說吐槽點真多之類的
They want to feel smart.
讓他們看完覺得爽快就行了
So, that's that.
就是這樣
Do you not trust your audience, Mr. Kakei?
筧先生 您不相信去看您作品的觀眾嗎？
What?
什麼？
Is that fun to write?
您寫這樣的東西有什麼樂趣？
You're an amateur. Don't butt in.
外行人少給我裝模作樣
I'm not a complete amateur.
我不算是完全的門外漢
I've been a manga editor for ten years.
我當了十年的漫畫編輯
I've always supported my writers.
我對我支持作者 帶他們走向未來的能力有自信
What are you saying?
你說什麼啊？
Writing's not fun at all!
寫作根本沒什麼樂趣
That's why I try to write as little as possible.
所以我才盡量不自己寫
What's fun is
有趣的是我拿賺來的錢
with the money I earned!
像這樣跟美女一起出遊啦
Don't do anything, Ms. Aoi.
小碧老師，請先稍安勿躁
Why? I can't sit still
為什麼？
Konishi… No, he's useless.
我要跟小西…
They'll just make fun of you. It's pointless.
如果鬧出什麼可笑的謠言就完蛋了
You're Aoi Minase.
您可是水無瀨碧老師
Don't do the dirty work. That won't look cool.
您不能有動作，這樣不體面
Please leave it to me.
交給我處理吧
Is it your job to get covered in mud?
當替死鬼就是你的工作嗎？
Is that why you took the blame for
所以你才會替由邊讓老師 頂下抄襲的罪名嗎？
Mr. Yube is a talented person.
由邊老師很有天分
Talent is a gift from the gods.
天分是上天的禮物
I protect that in any way I can.
我會全力去守護
Because that's my job.
這就是我的工作
But…
可是…
What should we do?
這要怎麼辦？
I'll go speak to Yuto from Silent Knife directly.
我現在要直接去找 Silent Knife悠人談判
If you do something like that,
你…你這樣做的話
you might get fired!
最慘可能會被開除喔
I don't think I'd get fired.
應該是不至於開除啦
Maybe a transfer to the records keeping department.
可能是被調去社史編纂室吧
Ms. Aoi. If that happens, please read
小碧老師，您要看我編的社史喔
What the hell is this?
這是什麼？
It's arranged by Mr. Tsuzuki.
都築先生編曲的
Don't joke with me.
喂，別開玩笑了
He ruined my song!
這樣會毀了我的歌
Hey, CEO. This is unacceptable, right?
社長
I'd say that's a personal opinion.
離不離譜是個人的主觀想法
Music is personal taste.
音樂只是一種個人喜好
I'm the one that got the genius producer, Katsuya Tsuzuki for you.
我可是親自去請了 鼎鼎大名的都築勝也製作人
Just do this for me, Yuto.
你就賣我個面子吧
This arrangement kills my music!
這種編曲根本是搞死我的曲子
He just added some cheap coating with electronic sounds on top.
只會寫一堆廉價的電音鋪在曲子上
The intro is so lame, too.
珍珠都要變假貨了
It sounds so fake!
前奏也很俗氣
Your sales are going down.
銷量下滑了啊
Your song sales are declining a bit by bit.
雖然還不明顯 但歌的銷量已經逐漸走下坡了
Once it starts declining,
直線下滑
It doesn't take much time until rock bottom!
這樣下去用不了多久 你就要跌落神壇了
That's why I said I'll do the movie!
所以我也去演了電影啊
Let me at least do my music the way I want.
音樂請讓我按照我的想法去做
We're not doing this job for looks or on a whim, either.
我幹這行可不是玩玩的，悠人
This is business.
這是生意
How did this outsider get in here?
無關的人進來幹什麼？
You're making the theme song for the movie!
這是要拿來當電影主題曲的歌
What's wrong with showing it to the editor?
請相關人士來聽有什麼關係？
No, I…
我說了…
I won't accept that arrangement!
不能用那種編曲！
It kills the song!
曲子會失去生命！
Who do you think helped the scrappy rat
你以為是誰收留了在餃子店打工 像老鼠一樣在路邊唱歌的你啊？
What the hell?
你說什麼？
Hey, CEO!
別打了，社長
Yuto! Calm down!
悠人也冷靜點！
Let's reschedule!
我們改天再約吧
We're sorry, Saneisha!
散英社的編輯先生，不好意思
Yuto.
悠人先生
I think this one's better.
我覺得這個編曲比較好
Right?
對吧？
Even an amateur could tell.
就連外行人都聽得出來吧
Even amateurs have hearts
外行人也有心
and the ability to feel.
也具有感受力
Oh, sorry.
抱歉
I don't think the quality of an arrangement is personal taste.
我認為編曲的好壞跟喜好無關
There's a right answer.
一定有正確解答
It's our job to find out what the best answer is.
尋找更好的答案就是我們的工作
"Our"?
我們？
For me, that's editing.
我本身是編輯
Oh, sure.
這樣啊
Yuto.
悠人先生
Just now, you said that the song would die.
剛才您說曲子會失去生命
Just like music has a life,
一如您的歌曲具有生命
stories have a life, too.
故事也有生命
What you're trying to do
你們要做的事情
based on this script is
從這個劇本來看
to kill the story.
就是要殺死故事
You're killing Aoi Minase's work.
殺死水無瀨碧老師的作品
You must know this.
您應該能明白吧
How much time was spent
要創造出讓人覺得有生命的東西
suffering and struggling
需要花費多少心血跟苦惱的時間
Creating isn't all fun.
絕不是靠樂在其中就能做出來的
I knew it from the start.
我很清楚
That this was unacceptable.
那樣的修改太離譜了
I used to be a street rat making 900 yen an hour at a gyoza shop
我曾在餃子店像老鼠一樣打工過活
and working part-time.
是個時薪只有九百圓的飛特族
But even then, I really loved Aoi Minase's novels.
我從那時就非常喜歡水無瀨碧的小說
Her words glistened
她的一字一句
like jewels and diamonds.
就像寶石一樣閃閃發光
I'm sorry.
對不起
Please apologize to Ms. Aoi for me.
請代我向老師道歉
Doctor Wataru.
涉師傅
I got a call from Mr. Yoshida.
吉田家的老先生剛剛打電話來
He said his knees hurt at night. He wants to talk to you.
他說晚上他的膝蓋都會疼痛 想找你商量
I'll talk to him.
-我去接吧 -沒關係，現在是午休
I told him you'd call back once you're free.
我跟他說等你有空會回電給他
Thank you. After I eat this.
謝謝你，我吃完就打
He just wants to talk to you.
吉田先生只是想找你聊天啦
Hello?
喂？
Yes, hello?
你好
What?
什麼？
I said, he just called me!
我說他剛才打給我了
He said he felt a rush to call me when he held his phone.
他說他一拿起手機 就忽然想要打給我
I see.
是喔
A date! A real date this time!
這一次
That's great.
太棒了
Telling him how you felt was worth it.
不枉費你努力追上去跟他告白
Yes. It's all thanks to you, Irino.
嗯，都是多虧有你
Because that time,
多虧你當時替我問他 誰是他無法忘懷的人
That opened the way for this!
一切就是由此開始的
All thanks to you!
都是你的功勞！
You better buy me lunch sometime.
下次請我吃飯喔
Really?
-真的嗎？ -是的
and recreate the whole thing.
會徹底重新製作
He said he'll say he won't do it unless they follow through.
至少悠人已經下了通牒 不這麼做他就不演了
Alright!
太棒了！
I just dropped by to tell you that.
那我今天只是來跟您說這件事
I'll be on my way.
我先走了
Wait, Soseki!
咦？漱石，你這裡
You have a little cut here.
你這裡受傷了
-I was so nervous. -What?
-好緊張 -什麼？
To see Silent Knife.
我是說Silent Knife
I've been to their Tokyo Dome concert with Sally before.
我之前跟沙沙一起去巨蛋 看過他們的演唱會
It's so nerve-wracking to assert myself to someone like that!
想到要跟他爭論就好緊張
I'm such a peasant.
我只是庶民啊
Yeah. He's a celebrity afterall.
對方是大明星嘛
OINTMENT
（軟膏）
All done.
好了
Thank you.
謝謝
Want a drink?
要喝點什麼嗎？
I don't really drink.
我不懂酒
We have Sora's Limoncello. It's sweet.
家裡有小空在喝的檸檬酒，是甜的
Thank you. I'll take that.
那我就不客氣了
Are you hungry?
你肚子餓啦？
I haven't eaten since this morning.
我從早上就沒吃東西
Right. You had a lot on your plate.
你奔波了一天呢
I'm sure you'll say no,
你可能不會想吃啦 不過我家有咖哩泡麵喔
I'd love that. At two minutes, 47 seconds.
我要吃，要泡2分47秒
The city was upside down.
因為能看到顛倒的街景
It was interesting.
很有趣
So sweet!
好甜
Good, right?
很好喝吧？
Yes. It's good.
嗯，很好喝
Thank you.
謝謝你
Good work. Thank you.
辛苦你了，謝謝你
You thanking me makes me
聽到您跟我說謝謝
really emotional.
我好感動
What?
什麼？
I became an editor
我
because I loved
是因為喜歡《勿忘我》
Don't Forget Me.
才會成為編輯的
I love The Scent of the Sky, too.
我也喜歡《聞見天空的氣味》
I joined Saneisha because I wanted to become
我是因為想成為您的責編
Aoi Minase's editor.
才會進入散英社的
Why do you say things like that now?
為什麼現在才告訴我？
I was never going to say it to you.
我本來打算一輩子都不說的
Idiot.
笨蛋
It happened
那是發生在等待泡麵泡好之前
while waiting for the cup noodles to cook.
那2分47秒內的事
Action!
開始！
Date my daughter!
《我家女兒交不到男朋友！》
WE'LL SHOW YOU THE BEHIND THE SCENES OF DATE MY DAUGHTER!
（《我家女兒交不到男朋友！》 幕後直擊）
Ow! Ouch!
好痛！
A SERIOUS KICK!
（全力一踢）
Show this in the bloopers.
一定要放到NG篇喔
TAIYAKI
（鯛魚燒）
You all have the expression of a parent.
大家的表情好像爸爸媽媽喔
We're so sorry.
實在非常抱歉
You told them?
你跟他說了嗎？
Will this love last?
戀愛總會結束嗎？
We're the strongest!
我們是最強母女
I'm scared of him hating me. I can't be honest.
害怕被討厭，不敢說真話
A story of a mom and a daughter.
這是母親與女兒的故事
I want to see it.
我想看這部小說
A Blood type O can't have a Blood type AB kid.
O型生不出AB型吧
We'll always be a mom and daughter.
母女永遠是母女